<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Forecasting on Shirin&#39;s playgRound</title>
    <link>/tags/forecasting/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Forecasting on Shirin&#39;s playgRound</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 13 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/forecasting/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Science for Business - Time Series Forecasting Part 3: Forecasting with Facebook&#39;s Prophet</title>
      <link>/2017/06/data-science-business-forecasting-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/06/data-science-business-forecasting-3/</guid>
      <description>In my last two posts (Part 1 and Part 2), I explored time series forecasting with the timekit package.
In this post, I want to compare how Facebook&amp;rsquo;s prophet performs on the same dataset.

Predicting future events/sales/etc. isn&amp;rsquo;t trivial for a number of reasons and different algorithms use different approaches to handle these problems. Time series data does not behave like a regular numeric vector, because months don&amp;rsquo;t have the same number of days, weekends and holidays differ between years, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Science for Business - Time Series Forecasting Part 2: Forecasting with timekit</title>
      <link>/2017/06/data-science-business-forecasting-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/06/data-science-business-forecasting-2/</guid>
      <description>In my last post, I prepared and visually explored time series data.
Now, I will use this data to test the timekit package for time series forecasting with machine learning.

Forecasting In time series forecasting, we use models to predict future time points based on past observations.
As mentioned in timekit&amp;rsquo;s vignette, &amp;ldquo;as with most machine learning applications, the prediction is only as good as the patterns in the data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Science for Business - Time Series Forecasting Part 1: EDA &amp; Data Preparation</title>
      <link>/2017/05/data-science-business-forecasting-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2017/05/data-science-business-forecasting-1/</guid>
      <description>Data Science is a fairly broad term and encompasses a wide range of techniques from data visualization to statistics and machine learning models. But the techniques are only tools in a - sometimes very messy - toolbox. And while it is important to know and understand these tools, here, I want to go at it from a different angle: What is the task at hand that data science tools can help tackle, and what question do we want to have answered?</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>