<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>ggplot2 on Shirin&#39;s playgRound</title>
    <link>https://shirinsplayground.netlify.app/tags/ggplot2/</link>
    <description>Recent content in ggplot2 on Shirin&#39;s playgRound</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 27 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://shirinsplayground.netlify.app/tags/ggplot2/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Good, the Bad and the Ugly: how to visualize Machine Learning data</title>
      <link>https://shirinsplayground.netlify.app/2021/04/goodbadugly_ml/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shirinsplayground.netlify.app/2021/04/goodbadugly_ml/</guid>
      <description>Below you’ll find the complete code and resources used to create the graphs in my talk The Good, the Bad and the Ugly: how to visualize Machine Learning data at this year’s Minds Mastering machines conference. You can find the German slides here:
 You can find Part 1: The Good, the Bad and the Ugly: how (not) to visualize data here.
If you have questions or would like to talk about this article (or something else data-related), you can now book 15-minute timeslots with me (it’s free - one slot available per weekday):</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>k-Means 101: An introductory guide to k-Means clustering in R</title>
      <link>https://shirinsplayground.netlify.app/2021/03/kmeans_101/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shirinsplayground.netlify.app/2021/03/kmeans_101/</guid>
      <description>Editor’s note: This is a guest post by Nathaniel Schmucker. He is the founder of The Analyst Code, a blog that provides tools to instill a love of data in individuals of all backgrounds and to empower aspiring analysts.
Introduction In this post, we will look at:
 What is a k-Means analysis? How does the k-Means algorithm work? How do we implement k-Means in R?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Good, the Bad and the Ugly: how (not) to visualize data</title>
      <link>https://shirinsplayground.netlify.app/2020/10/goodbadugly/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shirinsplayground.netlify.app/2020/10/goodbadugly/</guid>
      <description>Below you’ll find the complete code used to create the ggplot2 graphs in my talk The Good, the Bad and the Ugly: how (not) to visualize data at this year’s data2day conference. You can find the German slides here:
 You can also find a German blog article accompanying my talk on codecentric’s blog.
If you have questions or would like to talk about this article (or something else data-related), you can now book 15-minute timeslots with me (it’s free - one slot available per weekday):</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to combine point and boxplots in timeline charts with ggplot2 facets</title>
      <link>https://shirinsplayground.netlify.app/2017/11/combine_point_boxplot_ggplot/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shirinsplayground.netlify.app/2017/11/combine_point_boxplot_ggplot/</guid>
      <description>In a recent project, I was looking to plot data from different variables along the same time axis. The difficulty was, that some of these variables I wanted to have as point plots, while others I wanted as box-plots.
Because I work with the tidyverse, I wanted to produce these plots with ggplot2. Faceting was the obvious first step but it took me quite a while to figure out how to best combine facets with point plots (where I have one value per time point) with and box-plots (where I have multiple values per time point).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
