<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Pages on Shirin&#39;s playgRound</title>
    <link>https://shirinsplayground.netlify.app/page/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Pages on Shirin&#39;s playgRound</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://shirinsplayground.netlify.app/page/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Stillberatung</title>
      <link>https://shirinsplayground.netlify.app/page/stibe/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shirinsplayground.netlify.app/page/stibe/</guid>
      <description>Ich befinde mich gerade in Ausbildung zur ehrenamtlichen Stillberaterin der AFS und unterstütze Familien bei Fragen und Problemen rund um
 Stillvorbereitung in der Schwangerschaft (siehe auch Stillvorbereitungskurs) Stillen von Babys und Kleinkindern Stillen und Beikost Abstillen  Jede Familie, die stillen möchte, sollte die nötige Unterstützung bekommen, damit es von Anfang an ein positives Erlebnis wird. Ich möchte Familien dabei helfen, den für sich besten Weg zu finden, damit das Stillen gut gelingt und mit den individuellen Bedürfnisse aller Familienmitglieder langfristig vereinbar ist.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stillvorbereitungskurs</title>
      <link>https://shirinsplayground.netlify.app/page/stillvorbereitungskurs/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shirinsplayground.netlify.app/page/stillvorbereitungskurs/</guid>
      <description>Termin: Samstag, 26.11.2022 von 15 - 18 Uhr Ort: Hebammenpraxis Bauchladen Ostbevern Anzahl Teilnehmer: mindestens 3, maximal 10 (Teilnahme Einzeln oder als Paar möglich)Kosten: 15€ pro Person, bei Anmeldung als Paar: 20€ pro Paar Anmeldung: Anmeldungen bitter per E-Mail an shirin.elsinghorst@afs-stillen.de schicken. Beschreibung Ihr seid schwanger und habt euch über das Stillen bisher keine großen Gedanken gemacht? Vielleicht habt ihr schon Horrorstorys über zerkaute Brustwarzen und zu wenig Milch gehört und seid euch gar nicht sicher, ob ihr das mit dem Stillen schafft?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Conferences, webinars, podcasts, workshops, books, articles and the likes</title>
      <link>https://shirinsplayground.netlify.app/page/conferences_podcasts_webinars/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shirinsplayground.netlify.app/page/conferences_podcasts_webinars/</guid>
      <description>Here, you can find a list of all the talks I gave at conferences, webinars, podcasts, workshops, and all the other places you can and could hear me talk. You will also find a section with magazine articles and books I&amp;rsquo;ve written. :-)
If you have been enjoying my content and would like to help me be able to create more, please consider sending me a donation at paypal.me. Thank you!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Have a question - book me!</title>
      <link>https://shirinsplayground.netlify.app/page/bookme/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shirinsplayground.netlify.app/page/bookme/</guid>
      <description>Because I have been getting too many emails with questions and requests for help than I can answer, you can now book 15-minute time-slots with me. I will offer one 15-minute-slot per day on a first-come-first-serve basis. These 15 minutes will be free of charge and we will meet via Zoom, Skype or Google Meet. During these 15 minutes we can discuss your problem or question. Any help you might require beyond that, will have to be billed (details to be discussed in person).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Welcome to my page!</title>
      <link>https://shirinsplayground.netlify.app/page/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shirinsplayground.netlify.app/page/about/</guid>
      <description>I’m Shirin (Elsinghorst, born Glander), a biologist turned bioinformatician turned data scientist. During my PhD and Postdoc I worked with Next Generation Sequencing data. However, I then chose to become a data scientist for a German IT company, called codecentric. In this capacity, I have been working on many different projects, e.g. building fraud detection models, creating a chatbot, implementing predictive maintenance, and more. My preferred tool for data analysis has been R but I also work with Python.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
