<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>sketchnotes on Shirin&#39;s playgRound</title>
    <link>https://shirinsplayground.netlify.app/categories/sketchnotes/</link>
    <description>Recent content in sketchnotes on Shirin&#39;s playgRound</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 12 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://shirinsplayground.netlify.app/categories/sketchnotes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Sketchnotes from TWiML&amp;AI: Evaluating Model Explainability Methods with Sara Hooker</title>
      <link>https://shirinsplayground.netlify.app/2018/10/twimlai189/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shirinsplayground.netlify.app/2018/10/twimlai189/</guid>
      <description>These are my sketchnotes for Sam Charrington’s podcast This Week in Machine Learning and AI about Evaluating Model Explainability Methods with Sara Hooker:
Sketchnotes from TWiMLAI talk: Evaluating Model Explainability Methods with Sara Hooker
 You can listen to the podcast here.
  In this, the first episode of the Deep Learning Indaba series, we’re joined by Sara Hooker, AI Resident at Google Brain. I had the pleasure of speaking with Sara in the run-up to the Indaba about her work on interpretability in deep neural networks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sketchnotes from TWiML&amp;AI: Practical Deep Learning with Rachel Thomas</title>
      <link>https://shirinsplayground.netlify.app/2018/06/twimlai138/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shirinsplayground.netlify.app/2018/06/twimlai138/</guid>
      <description>These are my sketchnotes for Sam Charrington’s podcast This Week in Machine Learning and AI about Practical Deep Learning with Rachel Thomas:
Sketchnotes from TWiMLAI talk: Practical Deep Learning with Rachel Thomas
 You can listen to the podcast here.
 In this episode, i’m joined by Rachel Thomas, founder and researcher at Fast AI. If you’re not familiar with Fast AI, the company offers a series of courses including Practical Deep Learning for Coders, Cutting Edge Deep Learning for Coders and Rachel’s Computational Linear Algebra course.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sketchnotes from TWiML&amp;AI: Adversarial Attacks Against Reinforcement Learning Agents with Ian Goodfellow &amp; Sandy Huang</title>
      <link>https://shirinsplayground.netlify.app/2018/05/twimlai_adversarial_attacks/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shirinsplayground.netlify.app/2018/05/twimlai_adversarial_attacks/</guid>
      <description>These are my sketchnotes for Sam Charrington’s podcast This Week in Machine Learning and AI about Adversarial Attacks Against Reinforcement Learning Agents with Ian Goodfellow &amp;amp; Sandy Huang:
Sketchnotes from TWiMLAI talk: Adversarial Attacks Against Reinforcement Learning Agents with Ian Goodfellow &amp;amp; Sandy Huang
 You can listen to the podcast here.
 In this episode, I’m joined by Ian Goodfellow, Staff Research Scientist at Google Brain and Sandy Huang, Phd Student in the EECS department at UC Berkeley, to discuss their work on the paper Adversarial Attacks on Neural Network Policies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sketchnotes from TWiML&amp;AI #121: Reproducibility and the Philosophy of Data with Clare Gollnick</title>
      <link>https://shirinsplayground.netlify.app/2018/04/twimlai121/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shirinsplayground.netlify.app/2018/04/twimlai121/</guid>
      <description>These are my sketchnotes for Sam Charrington’s podcast This Week in Machine Learning and AI about Reproducibility and the Philosophy of Data with Clare Gollnick:
Sketchnotes from TWiMLAI talk #121: Reproducibility and the Philosophy of Data with Clare Gollnick
 You can listen to the podcast here.
 In this episode, i’m joined by Clare Gollnick, CTO of Terbium Labs, to discuss her thoughts on the “reproducibility crisis” currently haunting the scientific landscape.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sketchnotes from TWiML&amp;AI #124: Systems and Software for Machine Learning at Scale with Jeff Dean</title>
      <link>https://shirinsplayground.netlify.app/2018/04/twimlai124/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shirinsplayground.netlify.app/2018/04/twimlai124/</guid>
      <description>These are my sketchnotes for Sam Charrington’s podcast This Week in Machine Learning and AI about Systems and Software for Machine Learning at Scale with Jeff Dean:
Sketchnotes from TWiMLAI talk #124: Systems and Software for Machine Learning at Scale with Jeff Dean
 You can listen to the podcast here.
 In this episode I’m joined by Jeff Dean, Google Senior Fellow and head of the company’s deep learning research team Google Brain, who I had a chance to sit down with last week at the Googleplex in Mountain View.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sketchnotes from TWiML&amp;AI #115: Scaling Machine Learning at Uber with Mike Del Balso</title>
      <link>https://shirinsplayground.netlify.app/2018/03/twimlai115/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shirinsplayground.netlify.app/2018/03/twimlai115/</guid>
      <description>These are my sketchnotes for Sam Charrington’s podcast This Week in Machine Learning and AI about Scaling Machine Learning at Uber with Mike Del Balso:
Sketchnotes from TWiMLAI talk #115: Scaling Machine Learning at Uber with Mike Del Balso
 You can listen to the podcast here.
 In this episode, I speak with Mike Del Balso, Product Manager for Machine Learning Platforms at Uber. Mike and I sat down last fall at the Georgian Partners Portfolio conference to discuss his presentation “Finding success with machine learning in your company.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sketchnotes from TWiML&amp;AI #111: Learning “Common Sense” and Physical Concepts with Roland Memisevic</title>
      <link>https://shirinsplayground.netlify.app/2018/02/twimlai111/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shirinsplayground.netlify.app/2018/02/twimlai111/</guid>
      <description>These are my sketchnotes for Sam Charrington’s podcast This Week in Machine Learning and AI about Learning “Common Sense” and Physical Concepts with Roland Memisevic:
Sketchnotes from TWiMLAI talk #111: Learning “Common Sense” and Physical Concepts with Roland Memisevic
 You can listen to the podcast here.
 In today’s episode, I’m joined by Roland Memisevic, co-founder, CEO, and chief scientist at Twenty Billion Neurons. Roland joined me at the RE•WORK Deep Learning Summit in Montreal to discuss the work his company is doing to train deep neural networks to understand physical actions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sketchnotes from TWiML&amp;AI #94: Neuroevolution: Evolving Novel Neural Network Architectures with Kenneth Stanley</title>
      <link>https://shirinsplayground.netlify.app/2018/01/twimlai94/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shirinsplayground.netlify.app/2018/01/twimlai94/</guid>
      <description>These are my sketchnotes for Sam Charrington’s podcast This Week in Machine Learning and AI about Neuroevolution: Evolving Novel Neural Network Architectures with Kenneth Stanley:
Sketchnotes from TWiMLAI talk #94: Neuroevolution: Evolving Novel Neural Network Architectures with Kenneth Stanley
 You can listen to the podcast here.
 Kenneth studied under TWiML Talk #47 guest Risto Miikkulainen at UT Austin, and joined Uber AI Labs after Geometric Intelligence , the company he co-founded with Gary Marcus and others, was acquired in late 2016.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sketchnotes from TWiML&amp;AI #92: Learning State Representations with Yael Niv</title>
      <link>https://shirinsplayground.netlify.app/2018/01/twimlai92/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shirinsplayground.netlify.app/2018/01/twimlai92/</guid>
      <description>These are my sketchnotes for Sam Charrington’s podcast This Week in Machine Learning and AI about Learning State Representations with Yael Niv: https://twimlai.com/twiml-talk-92-learning-state-representations-yael-niv/
Sketchnotes from TWiMLAI talk #92: Learning State Representations with Yael Niv
 You can listen to the podcast here.
 In this interview Yael and I explore the relationship between neuroscience and machine learning. In particular, we discusses the importance of state representations in human learning, some of her experimental results in this area, and how a better understanding of representation learning can lead to insights into machine learning problems such as reinforcement and transfer learning.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sketchnotes from TWiML&amp;AI #91: Philosophy of Intelligence with Matthew Crosby</title>
      <link>https://shirinsplayground.netlify.app/2018/01/twimlai91/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shirinsplayground.netlify.app/2018/01/twimlai91/</guid>
      <description>These are my sketchnotes for Sam Charrington’s podcast This Week in Machine Learning and AI about Philosophy of Intelligence with Matthew Crosby: https://twimlai.com/twiml-talk-92-learning-state-representations-yael-niv/
Sketchnotes from TWiMLAI talk #92: Philosophy of Intelligence with Matthew Crosby
 You can listen to the podcast here.
 This week on the podcast we’re featuring a series of conversations from the NIPs conference in Long Beach, California. I attended a bunch of talks and learned a ton, organized an impromptu roundtable on Building AI Products, and met a bunch of great people, including some former TWiML Talk guests.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TWiMLAI talk 88 sketchnotes: Using Deep Learning and Google Street View to Estimate Demographics with Timnit Gebru</title>
      <link>https://shirinsplayground.netlify.app/2018/01/twimlai88_sketchnotes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shirinsplayground.netlify.app/2018/01/twimlai88_sketchnotes/</guid>
      <description> These are my sketchnotes taken from the “This week in Machine Learning &amp;amp; AI” podcast number 88 about Using Deep Learning and Google Street View to Estimate Demographics with Timnit Gebru:
Sketchnotes from TWiMLAI talk #88: Using Deep Learning and Google Street View to Estimate Demographics with Timnit Gebru
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Registration now open for workshop on Deep Learning with Keras and TensorFlow using R</title>
      <link>https://shirinsplayground.netlify.app/2017/12/keras_sketchnotes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shirinsplayground.netlify.app/2017/12/keras_sketchnotes/</guid>
      <description>Recently, I announced my workshop on Deep Learning with Keras and TensorFlow.
The next dates for it are January 18th and 19th in Solingen, Germany.
You can register now by following this link: https://www.codecentric.de/schulung/deep-learning-mit-keras-und-tensorflow
If any non-German-speaking people want to attend, I’m happy to give the course in English!
Contact me if you have further questions.
As a little bonus, I am also sharing my sketch notes from a Podcast I listened to when first getting into Keras:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Explaining Predictions of Machine Learning Models with LIME - Münster Data Science Meetup</title>
      <link>https://shirinsplayground.netlify.app/2017/12/lime_sketchnotes/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shirinsplayground.netlify.app/2017/12/lime_sketchnotes/</guid>
      <description>Slides from Münster Data Science Meetup These are my slides from the Münster Data Science Meetup on December 12th, 2017.
knitr::include_url(&amp;quot;https://shiring.github.io/netlify_images/lime_meetup_slides_wvsh6s.pdf&amp;quot;)  
My sketchnotes were collected from these two podcasts:
 https://twimlai.com/twiml-talk-7-carlos-guestrin-explaining-predictions-machine-learning-models/ https://dataskeptic.com/blog/episodes/2016/trusting-machine-learning-models-with-lime  Sketchnotes: TWiML Talk #7 with Carlos Guestrin – Explaining the Predictions of Machine Learning Models &amp;amp; Data Skeptic Podcast - Trusting Machine Learning Models with Lime
  Example Code  the following libraries were loaded:  library(tidyverse) # for tidy data analysis library(farff) # for reading arff file library(missForest) # for imputing missing values library(dummies) # for creating dummy variables library(caret) # for modeling library(lime) # for explaining predictions Data The Chronic Kidney Disease dataset was downloaded from UC Irvine’s Machine Learning repository: http://archive.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MICE (Multiple Imputation by Chained Equations) in R - sketchnotes from MünsteR Meetup</title>
      <link>https://shirinsplayground.netlify.app/2017/11/mice_sketchnotes/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://shirinsplayground.netlify.app/2017/11/mice_sketchnotes/</guid>
      <description>Last night, the MünsteR R user-group had another great meetup:
Karin Groothuis-Oudshoorn, Assistant Professor at the University of Twente, presented her R package mice about Multivariate Imputation by Chained Equations.
It was a very interesting talk and here are my sketchnotes that I took during it:
MICE talk sketchnotes
 Here is the link to the paper referenced in my notes: https://www.jstatsoft.org/article/view/v045i03
 “The mice package implements a method to deal with missing data.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
